Okay, well we are at Up the Creek
B&B, and it's up past Telegraph Creek,
past Glenora.
And I'm Barb.
And I'm Rick.
And we have lived here since 1973.
We never had a vehicle.
We walked everywhere.
And hitchhiked
Five and a half hours to town to
walk to town.
So we generally spent the night and come
back the next day.
If we went at all, yeah, it was
a trek.
But we covered a lot of miles walking,
packing kids.
Well when Ellen was a baby, we have
two.
One was born in 74.
Rosemary was born in 74.
Ellen was born in 77.
And by the time we had Ellen, we
had a vehicle.
Well the government had like a correspondence that
you mailed.
You mailed stuff back and forth.
And it was good, but it was always,
you know, like I looked upon it as
a job.
You know, like you got up and you
had to do this many hours.
And basically we just did it in the
morning, and they had the afternoon to do
chores and play and stuff and visit.
We visited a lot with neighbours.
So there were a lot of kids down
here.
And they would walk on the Iron Road.
The bears, we never had encounters when the
kids were little.
It's like the bears changed.
They became...
Well, the kids were making lots of noise.
That's true.
That's what helped.
That's true, yeah.
I used to call them my, yeah, my
bear bell.
Just keep chatting.
Yeah, kept the bears away, yeah.
I guess medical emergencies were the outstanding aspect
of, like a ruptured appendix in the middle
of the winter and using a dog team
to get to the clinic.
That was a scary incident.
This one room Rick built without any power
tools.
He did it all by hand except for
the floor.
He milled the, but we borrowed the sawmill
for that.
And yeah, so yeah, it was a lot
of hard work.
But that's just what you did.
You know, you didn't really think, you know,
getting up, oh my god, another day.
You know, you just had things to do
and you did them and went to bed
tired.
We didn't know about trap lines in those
days.
And we were, we lived on a guy's
trap line who, this was his lynx, his
prime lynx area.
And so right off the bat, come wintertime,
people would, but they wouldn't like come into
our house.
You know, they'd dog sled by and camp
at the creek and Rick would go down
and invite them up.
And you had to listen, you know, and
you have to, yeah.
Taught me lots.
Mm-hmm.
Like I always remember Fanny Woods and she,
she really welcomed all, all of us.
So she was a very hospitable place to
go and have tea with.
And she, and she said one day, she
says, you know, if you, if you freeze
your moose meat a little bit and grind
it, it's a lot easier.
And I came home and I tried it
and it worked.
And I started realizing that these, you know,
people have valuable things to share, but you
really have to stop, slow down, and listen.
Can I tell a quick story?
Yeah.
This, this was, this was, this is, was
one of the reasons why I stayed.
Yes.
Rick and I hitchhiked into town.
This was the year before.
This was in 72.
We caught a ride with the local minister.
There was an Anglican minister downtown.
His name was Reverend Wheeler.
But he wouldn't bring us into town.
He said, it's too dangerous.
And I was like, oh no, what are
we getting ourselves into?
But I, we realized later, he just didn't
want to be responsible bringing hippies in, you
know.
And so he dropped us off nine miles
the other side of town.
There was a little community that, that, that
mainly draft dodgers and Americans were at.
And so we, we didn't really join that
community.
We kind of camped on the road.
And we walked the nine miles into town.
And we're walking down the road in with
our packs.
And people used to sit, there was no
electricity, no TV.
And people used to sit in their porches.
And one, one guy came out and said.
Young, young fellow.
Yeah, I think, I think it was Harold
Hawkins who said to us, who are you
and where are you going?
And we said, oh we're Rick and Barb
and we're just going down to Glenora to
camp.
And so we kept going through.
And we, we got to Glenora.
And we stayed, I think, for about a
week.
And kind of looked around.
And Rick was like, yes, this is where
we, we, we have to live.
We just have to.
Should.
Yes.
And I, and I said, oh it's too,
too far.
Like it's, it's, it's daunting, it's so far.
And so we, so we finished our food.
And we started walking back to town.
And as we're walking through town, everybody would
stop and say, hi Rick, hi Barb, how
are you doing?
And the question in those days was what
animals did you see?
And it was, it was, I felt like
I'd come home.
You know, I felt like, I felt very,
very good about it.
People don't ask that so much anymore.
Although you always talk about the bears you
see coming up.
Well, I think the bears with these, this,
this is one of the things with the
helicopter activity.
The bears have gone down.
We haven't seen a bear in a couple
of days.
There's bears there.
Don't worry.
Bears and moose and wolverines.
Oh yes.
So we had wolves last winter.
They were all around our place.
Howling.
It was very eerie.
Rick would try to go out and communicate
with them, but I just, I didn't bother.
But yeah, let it, let it stay wild.
We've got a good wolf pack around, or
a good amount of wolves.
Lots of, lots of moose.
Lots of moose.
Elk are moving in.
And, and I think what I also would
like to see is that, that our grandchildren
would know this way of life.